译者｜微博@Emtee
字幕转制｜天外生物
感谢原字幕制作者
时光荏苒
As life progresses,
影像迷离
images blur.
独留回忆
All that remains are memories.
真真假假
Some of them true,some of them false.
我清楚地记得她
I remember her well.
至少我觉得是这样
At least I think I do.
她是一名战士
She was a warrior.
在旧时代 你必须
In the old century you had to be,
为生存而战
in order to survive.
悍 女
第一章
启示
吸气 呼气 就像她那样
Breathe in and out, the way she does.
现在 用力 快
And now, push. Now!
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
再见
Bye.
你过几天再来 对吗
See you in a couple of days, right?
妈妈
Mama...
走吗
Are you coming?
- 早上好  - 你好 莉兹
- Good morning!  - Hi, Liz!
给
Here.
我不准
莉兹 这孩子得学怎么开枪
Liz, the boy's gotta learn how to shoot.
我不允许
他不管怎么样都会学的
Well, he's gonna do it anyway.
在这学总好过偷偷在别处学
Better here than sneaking off somewhere else.
- 你吓到你母亲了  - 她不是我母亲
- You're scaring your mother.  - She ain't my mother.
要防备假先知
Beware of false prophets,
他们到你们这里来 外面披着羊皮
who come to you in sheep's clothing...
里面却是残暴的狼
For inwardly, they are ravening wolves.
耶稣是保护你们和你们家人
Jesus is the Shepherd who protects you
不受那些狼所害的牧羊人
and your family from those wolves.
而我是他的犬
And I am his dog.
让迷途羔羊
The sheepdog that gets the lambs back on track
重回正轨的牧羊犬
when they stray off the path.
你们有些人已经走入歧途了 对吗
And some of you have strayed, haven't you?
你们是怎么想的
What do you people think?
觉得神会同意?
That god is well disposed towards you?
我就直说吧
Let me set things straight.
应当离群的那些去的是地狱
Those who deserve it, go to hell.
我能跟你们讲讲地狱
I could tell you about hell.
讲讲那里的火焰
About its flames.
讲讲那里的痛苦
About the pain.
我肯定你们已经试想过那里的样子
I'm sure you people have tried to imagine what it's like.
实则更糟
It's worse.
惩罚要来临了
Retribution is coming.
现在我们唱歌吧
Now, let us join in singing.
与主同行
Abide with me.
你没事吧
You all right?
谢谢
Thank you.
你好 先生 这是我女儿 珊慕
How're you doing, sir? This is my daughter, Sam.
我儿子 马修 还有…
My boy, Matthew. And, uh...
我妻子
My wife.
你去哪了
Where were you?
那个人不是本地的
That man is a stranger here,
他还不认识这里的人
he doesn't know anybody yet.
我还以为你会有点同情心
I'd have expected a little more compassion from you.
怎么了 怎么了 怎么了
What's wrong? What's wrong? What's wrong?
深呼吸 好吗
Just breathe, all right?
呼吸 深呼吸就好
Breathe, just breathe.
大家都出去 我们不需要凑热闹的
Everybody outside.We don't need no busybodies.
出去啊 快出去
Go on, get. Get out!
- 会没事的  - 内森 我觉得你最好也出去
- You'll be all right.  - Nathan, I think you better go outside too.
有些事是男人不该看的
Some things aren't meant for a man's eyes.
会没事的 对吗 莉兹
It's gonna be just fine, right, Liz?
你会照顾好她的 对吧
You're gonna take care of her, right?
保证?
Promise?
我要出去了 好吗 我爱你 我爱你
I'm going to be right outside, okay? I love you. I love you.
你照顾好她
You take care of her.
把你身后的门关上
Close the door behind you.
会没事的 亲爱的
It's gonna be all right, honey.
孩子的头太大了
The baby's head is too big.
什么意思
What's that supposed to say?
我们得在孩子和母亲之间做出选择
We're going to have to choose between the baby and the mother.
没法同时救两个
Can't save both of them.
必须都救
You have to.
你母亲说一切都会好的
Your mother said everything would be all right.
不要 我想待着 我想帮忙
No, I wanna stay. I wanna help.
嘿 里面怎么样了
Hey... how's it going in there?
一切都好吗
Everything all right?
是吗
Yeah?
用力 阿比 使出全力 加把劲
Push, Abby. Hard as you can now, come on!
好样的
Good girl!
孩子在哪
Where's the baby?
我想看看我的孩子 他在哪
I wanna see my baby. Where is he?
把我的孩子给我
Give me my baby!
这不是你的错
It ain't your fault.
耶和华赐予了 耶和华又拿走了
The lord gives and the lord takes away.
这和耶和华无关
这和牧师有关
牧师？
The reverend?
莉兹
Liz...
牧师是神的代表
The reverend is a man of god.
你所认为的并不是事实
You're seeing things that ain't there.
耶稣死后复活了
If Jesus came back to life after he was dead...
阿比盖尔的孩子不会吗
Couldn't that happen to Abigail's baby, too?
你能给我涂脸吗
Can you face-paint me?
你能帮我一下吗
我忙着呢 看不出吗
I'm doing something. Can't you tell?
我们来看下情况
We've come to see if everything's all right.
一切正常
Everything's just fine.
你们无需浪费时间
No reason for you folks to go wasting your time.
我们想亲眼看下
We'd like to look for ourselves.
最好不要 医生一小时后就到
Rather not. There's a doctor coming in an hour,
他看更好
it's better if he takes a look.
牧师安排的
The reverend arranged it.
你们好
Hello!
- 什么情况  - 莉兹
- What the hell?  - Liz!
莉兹
Liz!
下来 莉兹
You get down here, Liz!
下来
You get down here!
我要看到你的脸
I wanna see your face.
内森 别把气出在我儿子身上
Nathan! Don't take it out on my boy!
我们能好好谈谈
We can talk about this like decent folk!
我跟你没过节 伊莱
I got no quarrel with you, Eli!
我是来找你妻子的
I'm here for your wife.
她得为她的罪行受到惩罚
She's gotta be punished for her sins.
她得在火刑柱上被烧死
She's gotta burn at the stake, Eli!
理智些 内森
Try to be reasonable now, Nathan.
我理解你的悲痛 相信我
I know your sorrow, believe me.
我也失去过心爱之人 记得吗
I lost a loved one too, remember?
我知道你的悲痛让你失去了理智
I know you're out of your mind with grief,
但相信我 你的痛苦会过去的 就和我的一样
but believe me, your pain will pass, just like mine did!
我能很容易地接受你说的
I could accept that real easy,
只要那个没舌头的谋杀犯死在火刑柱上
as long as that tongueless murderess ends up at the stake!
我要她受到惩罚
I demand retribution!
你知道她做了什么吗 伊莱
You know what she did, Eli?
她杀了我的宝贝儿子
She murdered my baby boy.
就在他能受洗之前 她杀了他
Before he could even be baptized, she murdered him.
现在他会怎么样
What's gonna happen to him now?
你觉得他会找到救赎吗
Do you think he's gonna find salvation?
你知道她怎么做的吗 伊莱
You know how she did it, Eli?
我看过他
I seen him.
他的大脑外露
His brains had leaked out.
你妻子弄裂了他的头骨
Your wife broke his skull.
她破开了他的头骨
She cracked his skull wide open!
她该为此下地狱
She should go to hell for this!
够了
That will be enough.
你遭受着痛苦…
There has been suffering...
威士忌让你胡言乱语
It is the whiskey talking now.
当下解决不了问题
This is not the moment to solve this.
她该下地狱 牧师
She belongs in hell, reverend.
他伤到你了吗
Did he do you any harm?
不要让牧师进来
他刚刚帮我们脱离了困境
He just helped us out of a real fix.
我也能来一杯吗
Do I get one, too?
你还太年轻
You ain't old enough for that yet.
干嘛对这孩子这么苛刻
Why be so hard on the boy?
他为了保护家人才有所行动
He only acted to protect his family.
他这样做就是成年人了
That makes him an adult.
他母亲不希望他摆弄枪
His mother doesn't want him playing with guns.
年轻人想手持步枪是很自然的事
It's natural for a young man to want to hold a rifle in his hands.
我能把我这杯给马修喝吗
May I offer my glass to Matthew?
我想你该去睡觉了 马修
I think it's about time you went back to bed, Matthew.
- 爸爸  - 快 喝了
- Aw, dad!  - Come on, drink up.
如果那孩子
None of this would have happened
健康完好地被生下 就不会有这种事
if that baby had been born in perfect health.
但莉兹对此无能为力
But Liz couldn't do nothing about that.
她决定了谁生谁死
She decided who was to live and who was to die.
那个决定属于神 也只属于神
That decision belongs to god, and god only.
她为什么不把那个选择给留给他呢
Why did she not leave that choice up to him?
也许我该去把她带来
Maybe I should go fetch her.
我知道你在那里
I know you're there,
我也知道你能听到我说话
and I know you can hear me.
或许你没舌头
You may have no tongue,
但你的耳朵没问题
but there is nothing wrong with your ears.
你心中为什么会起疑
Why do doubts rise in your heart?
你为什么会烦恼
Why are you troubled?
你晚上怎么入睡的
How do you sleep at night?
做谋杀犯是什么感觉
How does it feel to be a murderess?
你知道我为什么来这里吗
Do you know why I'm here?
我是来惩罚你的
I'm here to punish you.
你爱这个家吗
Do you love this family?
我见过你女儿了
I've looked at your daughter.
她就快是个年轻女人了
She's almost a young woman already.
你在这啊
There you are.
我得走了
I must be going.
对内森请不要怀恨在心
Please don't bear a grudge against Nathan in your heart.
失去孩子是最难以承受的事
Losing a child is the worst thing a body can go through.
我刚跟你妻子也这么说了
I was just talking to your wife about that same thing.
你都没感谢他
You didn't even thank him.
实际上 你都没有跟他打招呼
Fact is, you didn't even say hello to him.
我们必须离开这里
莉兹 内森会恢复理智的
Liz, Nathan will come around.
对了 你知道吗
Right, you know what?
给我一两天时间
Give me a couple of days.
我找人来看管羊
I'll get someone to come in for the sheep...
然后我们去我爸那里待一段时间
And then we'll go up to my pa's for a bit.
反正那里就他一个人
He's all alone up there anyway.
爸爸
Dad?
待在这里
我要去谈谈 这得有个了结
I'm just going to talk. This has got to stop.
先是开枪打我们的窗户 现在又这样
First shootin' our windows up, now this.
驾 走吧
Yah! Come on!
驾 驾
Yah! Yah!
我要你和你母亲待在一起
I want you to stay with your mother.
她不是我母亲
She ain't my mother.
- 马修  - 你会需要我帮忙的
- Matthew!  - You're gonna need my help.
好吧 只要你别惹麻烦
All right, as long as you stay outside.
但我为什么不能进去玩呢
But why can't i just play inside?
我要你在我身旁
为什么
Why?
因为我说了算
我为什么不能帮忙
And why can't I help out?
别再问问题了 你待在这里唱唱歌
我觉得现在可以把遮眼布摘掉了
I think we can take that blindfold off, now.
但我保证过
But I promised.
你母亲不会介意
Your mother won't mind.
她有很多事要做
She has a lot to do.
好了 看见没
Here, see?
一切都会好的
Everything will be fine.
妈妈呢
And mama?
她得在谷仓干活
She had to work in the barn.
她不想你过去 记得吗
And she did not want you there, do you remember?
我想和你谈谈你的母亲
I would like to talk to you about your mother.
内森
Nathan!
他们搬走了
They've gone and moved.
莉兹
Liz?
你在哪
Where are you?
他带走了珊慕
别 内森离开了 阿比盖尔也是
No, no, Nathan's gone. And Abigail.
收拾好 搬走了
Packed up, moved out.
牧师 他把我锁在谷仓里
你去哪了
Oh! Where'd you get to, huh?
你吓到你母亲了
You scared your mother.
你让她担心死了
Had her worried sick.
要我给你涂脸吗
今天下午 你和牧师说了些什么
他说到我了吗
妈妈 你是邪恶的吗
Mama, are you evil?
牧师说你杀了一个人
The reverend said you murdered a man.
他说他是来惩罚你的
He says he's here to punish you.
要把你带回他来的地方
To take you back where he came from.
为什么
Why?
因为她爱你
Because she loves you.
开枪打死我
Shoot me.
在你身后
Behind you.
求你了
Please.
终结我的痛苦
Stop the pain.
带她们去爷爷那
Take them to grandpa.
妈妈 妈妈
Mama? Mama?
是那个牧师 他把我弄醒了
It was the reverend. He woke me up.
驾 驾
Yah! Yah!
第二章
出走
[粤语]嘿 你是谁 叫什么名字
[粤语]阿明 她醒了
[粤语]下车
[粤语]快点下车
乔安娜 我叫乔安娜
Joanna. My name is Joanna.
[粤语]我要把她卖给弗兰克 赚一笔钱
[粤语]- 不要啊  - 闭嘴
[弗兰克的地狱]
弗兰克
Frank!
阿明
Meng!
[粤语]你好啊
[粤语]喂 我有好东西给你
[粤语]我就下来
[粤语]漂亮点才行 过来
[粤语]把头发放下来
阿明 瞧瞧你 你个混蛋发财了啊
Meng, you prosperous fucker, you. Look at you.
这位是？
And what do we have here?
我叫乔安娜
My name's Joanna.
很高兴认识你
Well, it is a pleasure to meet you.
来 转一圈 让我看看你
Come on now, spin around, let me get a look at you.
不错啊
There you are.
- 莎莉  - 什么事
- Sally!  - Yeah.
你能弄杯冰柠水
Would you be so kind as to treat Joanna here
招待下这边的乔安娜吗
to a glass of cold lemonade?
当然可以 来吧 亲爱的
Yeah, but of course. Come, honey.
好了 阿明 我们来谈正事
All right, meng, let's talk fucking Turkey.
给
Here you go.
看呐 新来的
Lookie here! Fresh meat.
一口吞了 小姑娘
Swallow it right on down, girlie.
很快你就要吞别的东西了
Soon you'll be swallowing something else.
- 你叫什么 姑娘  - 乔安娜
- What's your name, girl?  - Joanna.
你爸爸带你来的吗
Did your daddy bring you here?
不是? 你确定吗
No? Are you sure?
难道他不是觉得你漂亮
Didn't he just think you were so good,
他得让这世上的其他人也知道?
he had to let the rest of the world in on it, too?
你以为你能去哪啊
Whoa, there now, where do you think you're going?
他们没带上我就走了
They're leaving without me!
没错 但别担心
Yes, they are, but don't you worry about a thing
因为从现在起 你就住这了 亲爱的
'cause from now on, this is where you live, darling.
就这里
Right here.
好了 去弄弄干净吧
Now, come on now. Let's get you cleaned up.
没错
Yes.
嘘 嘘
Shh, shh.
爽 爽
Yeah, yeah!
所以那就是我们在这做的工作
So that's the work we do around here.
我们只要一直呻吟
And we do all the moaning and groaning
就能确保更快完事
because that makes sure it's over faster.
- 为什么  - 为什么 因为男人喜欢
- Why?  - Why? That's what men like.
那么…你出过血吗
So, um... You ever bled yet?
你两腿之间 亲爱的
'Twixt your legs, honey.
这没什么羞耻的 出过吧?
It's nothing to be ashamed of. You have, haven't you?
对吗 好吧 这暂且是
Yeah? Well, then, that's gonna be our little secret
我们的小秘密 好吗
for the time being, okay?
现在 你去睡吧
Now, you go to bed.
你是谁
And who are you?
你叫什么 姑娘
What's your name, girl?
乔安娜
Joanna.
弗兰克 跟她上楼什么价
Frank, what's it cost to go upstairs with this one?
拜托 弗雷德 你出不起
Come on now, Fred, you cannot afford her.
我不这么认为
Oh, I don't know about that.
今天我的牌运可他妈好了
I got pretty damn lucky at cards today.
嘿 伊士曼
Hey, eastman.
我欲火焚身 想和你做
I'm horny as hell and I feel like doing you!
给你免费来一炮怎么样
What would you say to a free ride, huh?
这可不是你说了算
That ain't yours to decide.
钱我自己出
I'll pay for it myself.
该死 莎莉 这种事你一直瞒着我 是吗
Damn, Sally, what, you been holding out on me now, huh?
这样可以 但她得看着
I'll go along with that. But then she gets to watch.
- 不行  - 那就算了
- No way.  - Then, it's no deal.
我觉得这是个好主意
Oh, it sounds like a fine idea to me.
我肯定这会很有教育意义
It'll be most educational, I'm sure.
怎么了 你不喜欢吗 宝贝
What's wrong, don't you like it, honeybunch?
爽
Oh, yeah.
打我
Hit me.
- 什么  - 打我
- What?  - Hit me!
不行 我不会那么做
No, I ain't gonna do that.
打我啊 该死的
Hit me, god damn it!
这样可不行 伊士曼
I'm not taking this, eastman.
再打我
Hit me again.
Hit me again!
别 别 别 别 别开枪
No, no, no, no, don't shoot!
别开枪 我没关系 乔安娜
Don't shoot. I don't mind it, Joanna.
这只是场游戏 对吧
It's just a game, right?
再动手我就开枪了
You do that again and I'm going to shoot.
请把枪放下
Please put the gun down.
你敢 继续对准我
Don't you ever. Just keep pointing it at me.
你敢放下枪试试
Don't you dare drop that gun on me.
这就对了 继续对准我
That's right. Keep pointing it at me.
你敢放下试试
Don't you dare.
我要掐死她
I'm gonna strangle the life out of her!
开枪打我啊
Shoot me!
动手啊 乔安娜 开枪打我 该死的
Do it, Joanna. Shoot me, god damn it!
开枪啊 该死 婊子
Shoot, god damn it, bitch!
我能看出你会是个不错的小妓女
You're gonna make a fine little whore, i can see that already.
我打赌你也能把我弄得非常干净
I just bet that you can make me real nice and clean too.
或许全世界把我们美丽的城市毕斯玛司
The whole world may see our fair city of bismuth
看成是索多玛和蛾摩拉
as a place of sodom and gomorrah,
但规矩在这里是管用的
but rules do apply here.
不准妓女射杀客人还不受惩罚
A whore cannot be allowed to shoot down her customers with impunity.
我哥哥经营地狱酒馆是为了
My brother runs the inferno as a place
让辛勤工作的矿工们
where hard-working miners
能找到应得的消遣
can find well-deserved recreation.
这必须保持下去
That must remain so,
也会保持下去
and so it will.
让此事警示所有人吧
Let this be an example.
别这样…
Come on now...
一个矿镇需要有组织的娱乐
A mining town has a need for organized entertainment.
我得让这里的客人感到安全
And I need to know that customers here feel safe.
所以我把我弟弟齐克带到了毕斯玛司
That's why I brought my brother Zeke to bismuth.
他是个好警长 这个镇配不上他
He's a better sheriff than this town deserves.
地狱酒馆的每个人都知道
Everybody at the inferno knows
一个姑娘哪怕抓伤了客人
that if a girl so much as scratches a customer
她都会受到惩罚
she's gonna be punished.
所以莎莉知道她会面临什么
So Sally knew what she had coming.
可他吊死她了
But he strangled her.
是啊…我知道 我也很难过
Yeah... I know, it hurt me too.
该死的 她是跟我最久的员工之一
Damn, she was one of my oldest employees.
但是规矩是规矩
But rules are rules.
你不守规矩 你就有罪
If you don't obey the rules, you're guilty.
你有罪 你就要付出代价
And if you're guilty, you're gonna pay.
你明白的 对吗
You understand that, don't you? Hmm?
告诉我你明白
Tell me you understand.
你知道我第一次跟女孩上床是几岁吗
You know how old i was when I first went to bed with a girl?
我二十一岁
I was 21.
二十一
Twenty-one.
那时齐克十四岁
While Zeke, he was 14.
而我还得偷看
I got to watch, though.
从窥孔里偷看他
I spied on him through the peephole.
那之前 我一直不理解其中的乐趣
I never did see what all the fuss was about.
也不理解大家所谈论的那些事
You know, what everybody talked about.
我理解不了
I couldn't see it.
你不再是个孩子了
You're not a child anymore.
我不是很久了
I haven't been for a long time.
是时候了
The time has come.
我会温柔的
I'm gonna be gentle.
就是这样
That's right.
帅哥 你好棒
Oh, stud, you sure are good.
乔安娜
Joanna!
弗兰克要决斗了
Frank is in a gunfight!
嘿 搞什么啊 我就快完事了
Hey, what the hell! I'm almost done.
你看到没
You see that?
下次让她一起来 你觉得如何
What do you say we have her join us next time?
他来了
Here he is.
这是我和弗兰克之间的事
This is just between me and frank.
我只要一场公平对决
All I want is a fair fight.
那你来这里干嘛
Then what are you doing here?
让他爽进地狱吧
Blow him to hell!
没错
Yeah!
我不是个暴力的人
I'm not a violent man.
我常和数字打交道
I usually work with numbers.
但现在我站在你面前
But now, I'm standing here in front of you
是要开枪打死你 弗兰克
to shoot you dead, frank.
我女儿因你而死
My daughter is dead because of you.
你这样的男人觉得自己的所作所为不会有后果
It's men like you who think their actions have no consequences,
你这样的男人在使这国家变样
who are making the country turn into what it's turning into.
所以为了我的女儿
So, for my daughter's sake,
为了每一个人的女儿
for every daughter's sake,
我不得不杀了你
I have to kill you.
因为我是一位父亲
Because I am a father.
所以你会数数
So you can count.
也会讲屁话
And you can sure as shit talk.
但我们都想知道的是
But what we all wanna know is,
你会开枪吗
can you shoot?
我们什么时候私奔
So, when do we elope?
去哪
Where to?
哪都行
Anywhere.
只要是我们能得到自由的地方
Wherever we can be free.
但我们在这也算自由
But we are free here. Sort of.
不算
No, we're not.
你知道的
And you know it.
给我涂脸
Face-paint me.
什么
What?
用你的手指涂我的脸
Paint my face with your fingers.
你让我想起了我的妻子
You, uh, remind me of my wife.
但你衣着更美 闻上去更香 长得更漂亮
But you dress better, you smell better, you look better.
谢谢
Thank you.
不准接吻
No fucking kissing.
我说了 不准接吻
I said, no kissing!
不准接吻 该死的
No kissing! God damn it!
你要请我喝酒还怎么
So, are you gonna buy me that drink, or what?
当然 威士忌
Sure. Whiskey.
我警告过你了 你个狗娘养的
I warned you, you son of a bitch!
没人能吻我 懂吗
Nobody kisses me, do you understand?
该死的婊子 你咬掉了我的舌头
Fucking whore, you bit my tongue off.
弗兰克 弗兰克
Frank? Frank?
姑娘 这次你居然真咬了
Oh, girl, you really gone and done it now.
我警告了他六次
I warned him six times!
你警告的那家伙是金矿上的重要人物
Well, the fella you warned is kind of important up at the gold mine.
现在我的酒馆里全他妈是
Now, I got me a whole saloon
喝醉的白痴 全叫着要给惩罚
full of drunken fucking idiots all howling for retribution.
叫他们见鬼去吧
Tell 'em to go fuck themselves.
给他们免费喝一杯好了
Give them a drink on the house or something.
你们觉得我会因为你们这些姑娘
Well, you think I'm gonna waste my hard-earned money
坏了规矩而浪费我辛苦赚来的钱?
because you girls refuse to obey the fucking rules?
给我起来 快走
Get the fuck up! Come on!
- 出来  - 去你们妈的
- Get out there!  - Fuck you!
迈克在哪
Now, where's Mike?
我要她受到惩罚
I demand retribution!
她会的 迈克
You're gonna get it, Mike.
瞧 毕斯玛司的规矩很明确
You see, the rules in bismuth are clear,
所有客人都会得到应有的尊重
and all customers will get the respect they got coming.
吊死这愚蠢的妓女
Hang the stupid whore!
不行 伊丽莎白不会被吊死
No, no, Elizabeth here, she's not gonna hang.
必须吊死她 弗兰克
Gotta hang her, frank!
迈克现在也没死 对吗
Mike ain't dead now neither, is he?
但他因她的无法无天而受害
But he was a victim of her lawlessness,
所以他能给个提议
so he gets to make a fucking proposal.
会是什么提议呢 迈克
Now what's it gonna be, Mike? Huh?
你想免费干她一周? 是这样吗
You want this free pussy for a week? Is that it?
你给我把那婊子的舌头割了
You cut that fucking bitch's tongue off!
你想以物换物 是吧 迈克
You want a trade, Mike, huh?
你想以眼还眼? 你是想这样吗 迈克
You want an eye for an eye? Is that what you want, Mike?
每天用酒精冲洗五次
Rinse it five times a day with alcohol
应该会比你预料的要愈合得更快
and it should heal up sooner than you'd think.
不能吃固体食物 不能口交
No solid foods. No blow jobs.
她还能再说话吗
Will she ever be able to talk again?
没太大可能
Not much chance of that.
给
Here you go.
[聋哑人手语词典]
再见
Goodbye.
我
I...
跳舞
Dance...
在周二?
On Tuesday?
我只喝酒
I only drink
在周二
on Tuesdays.
我只在周二喝酒
I only drink on Tuesdays.
我
I...
杀
Kill...
弗兰克?
Frank?
这是自杀
That's suicide.
但他们会追捕你
But they'll come after you.
此外 你怎么打算呢
Besides, what're you gonna do?
去别的妓院工作吗
Work in some other cathouse?
请别那么做
Please don't do it.
我无法忍受对你的思念
I couldn't stand to miss you.
别以为
Don't think
这地方无法纪 不敬神
just because this is a lawless, godless place
你们的所作所为就不会有后果
that your actions will go without consequences.
女士们 你们想死后下地狱吗
Ladies, do you want to end up in hell?
漂亮的衣服愚弄不了任何人
The nice clothing doesn't fool anybody.
我知道你们是谁
I know who you are
我知道你们是什么
and I know what you are.
你们的父亲知道后会怎么想
What would your fathers think if they knew?
你们的母亲会落泪
Your mothers weep.
你们的父亲会因耻辱而挖出自己的眼睛
Your fathers pluck out their eyes in shame!
[婚姻中介]
你好
Good day.
我有东西给你 进来吧
I have something for you.Come.
我已经找到了一个人
I've managed to find someone who doesn't mind
他不介意娶没舌头的女人
marrying a woman without a tongue,
不过路有些远
but it will take some traveling.
他六个月前就是个鳏夫了
He's been a widower since the last six months.
他在找一个会下厨的妻子
He's looking for a wife who can cook
还要不介意他有个儿子
and who doesn't mind that he already has a son.
跟我猜的差不多
No, I figured as much.
我们会热情地欢迎你
"We will welcome you with open arms
并保证让你尽快有家的感觉
"and make sure you feel right at home, as quickly as possible.
敬上 等等等等 这里有张照片
"Respectfully yours." And so on and so forth, and there's a picture.
你会有个真正的家庭
You're gonna have a real family.
我要怎么做呢
How am I gonna do that?
我们是姐妹?
We're sisters?
弗兰克会杀了我们
Frank would kill us.
不行 世事难料
No, you never know.
等你获得你新丈夫的信任后
And when you've convinced your new husband,
你能从那边帮我付马车费
you can pay for the stagecoach from down there.
你觉得你的行程要多久
How long you think you'll need?
你们两个得马上出来
You two gotta come right away.
某个家伙刚付了一大笔现金
Some fella just paid a whole pile of cash
包下了地狱酒馆 你们快点
to buy out the inferno. Get your asses moving.
你最后一晚还得工作
Your last night and you got to work too.
好了 听好
All right now, listen up!
我们在月末通常赚不到钱
Usually, we don't earn Jack-shit at the end of the month.
贾姬 你他妈给我马上闭嘴
Jackie, shut the fuck up right fucking now
不然我他妈亲手让你闭上
or I'm gonna fucking make you.
这个客人是天赐之福
This customer right here is a godsend
他今晚把你们全包下了
and he bought the right to all of y'all this evening
要是他成了常客
and if he becomes a regular customer,
我就会丰厚地奖赏你们
well, you can all expect a big, fat, fucking bonus, courtesy of me.
但我要你们完全保证
But I demand total commitment here.
不管发生什么
I mean, whatever happens,
不管他他妈想要什么
whatever the fuck he wants,
他都会得到满足
he is gonna get it.
如果有人
Now if anybody,
有人做了什么 给我毁了这事
I mean, anyone does anything to ruin it for me...
就会受到惩罚
Well, they're gonna be punished.
会受到比以前更严重的惩罚
Shit, they're gonna be punished worse than I've punished anyone before.
总之 你们好好表现
But with that fucking said, you do a good job, and, uh,
他就会都要了
shit, he'll take you all.
这事要给我办成
I want this one.
好了 快来
All right now, come on!
你会喜欢这排场的
You are gonna like this.
没错 就是这样
That's right, there you are.
我的小宝贝们
My little doves.
看呐
Now, will you look at that, huh?
这两个很年轻 很嫩
These two right here, they're real young, real fresh.
没被动过 你懂的
Untouched, if you know what I mean.
我们这里各种各样的都有
We got all kinds here.
我们有中国人 如果你喜欢这种的话
We've got Chinese, if you like that kind of thing.
这一个 她叫贾姬
Oh, this one here, she's Jackie.
我能看出 贾姬喜欢你
Jackie likes you, i can tell.
你想要的 我们这里都有
We've got anything you want here.
你内心的所有欲望
All your heart's desire.
就在地狱酒馆里
Right here in the inferno.
这一个 她性子很烈
Oh, this one here, well, she got a fire in her.
我不得不割了她的舌头
And I had to cut out her tongue
让她听话
just to keep her in line.
幸好她没法回嘴
Good thing, she can't talk back.
先生 你很有品位
You have fine taste, sir.
这一个 她对我来说是个谜
This one right here, well, she is a mystery to me.
她是我从一伙游历的浪人那买下的
I bought her from a band of traveling gypsies.
你懂的 多种多样
You know, colorful types.
该死 我都不知道她的真名
Damn, I don't even know her real name.
就是她
She's the one.
选得太好了 先生
Well, that's an excellent choice, sir.
我能推荐其他几个姑…
May I suggest a couple of other gi...
就只要她
Only her.
但你包下的是整个地狱酒馆
But you paid for the whole inferno.
我包下是不想被人看到这种事
I paid not to be seen doing this.
今晚花了我很多钱
This evening has cost me a lot of money.
你的声音有什么问题吗 你不能说话吗
Is there something wrong with your voice? Can't you talk?
我能说话
Yes, I can.
你想要我给你跳舞吗
Would you like me to dance for you?
为了找到你 我不得不等待很久
I had to wait a long time to find you.
我非常失望 我想过很多情况 但不是这种
I am very disappointed. I had considered many things, but not this.
这就是你想要的吗
Is this what you wanted?
这就是你所追求的吗
What you looked for?
我已准备好原谅你所有的罪
I am prepared to forgive all your sins.
我也有罪
I have also sinned.
我会在地狱中被永远焚烧
I am going to burn in hell forever.
我放弃了去天堂的权利
I gave up the right to go to heaven.
但是你让我这么做的
But you made me do it.
只有你能拯救我
And only you can save me.
- 别这样  - 没错
- No.  - Yes.
我有罪是因为我们应该先完成仪式
I have sinned because we should have finished the ceremony first.
这是使徒保罗写在哥林多前书里的
Paul, the apostle, wrote it in the first corinthians.
- 帮帮我 乔安娜  - 我帮不了
- Help me, Joanna.  - I can't.
那我们两个都会下地狱
Then we shall both burn in hell.
我是来拯救你的 好让你能拯救我
I am here to save you, so that you can save me.
我会让你这么做的 你知道我会的
I will make you do it. You know I will.
我不会让你再那么做了
I won't let you do that again.
我会先杀了你
I'll kill you first.
我尝试了 你让我别无选择
I tried. You leave me no choice.
救命 来人啊
Help! Somebody... ah!
来人救命啊
Somebody, help! Ah!
- 你是我的 这是神的旨意  - 救命
- You are mine! It is god's will!  - Help!
救命
Help!
救命 来人啊
Help! Somebody!
出去
Get out!
你个贱人
You whore!
今晚你要跟我走
You're coming with me tonight.
我需要你的帮助
I need your help.
你不会让我惹上麻烦 对吗
You're not gonna get me into trouble, are you?
你确定吗
Are you sure about this?
好了
All right.
我办不到
I can't do this.
你是伊丽莎白·布兰迪吗
Are you Elizabeth brundy?
你确定你要开始这段行程吗
Are you sure you're up to making this trip?
好运
Well, good luck.
别让人看到伤口 依然很新
Don't let anyone see that for a while. It's still pretty fresh.
第三章
起因
我们在天上的父
愿人都尊你的名为圣
愿你的国降临
愿你的旨意行在地上 如同行在天上
我们日用的饮食今日赐给我们
免我们的债
And forgive us our trespasses,
如同我们免了人的债
as we forgive those who trespass against us.
不叫我们遇见试探
And lead us not into temptation,
但救我们脱离凶恶
but deliver us from evil.
因为国度
For thine is the kingdom
权柄 荣耀 全是你的
and the power and the glory,
直到永远 阿门
forever and ever. Amen.
就今晚吧
Tonight.
乔安娜还是在讲荷兰语
Joanna is still speaking Dutch.
我要追究你的责任
I hold you responsible for that.
我会祈求耶和华的帮助
I'll pray for the lord's assistance.
作为妻子 你有你的职责
As a wife, you have your duties.
妻子对自己的身体没有主权
"The wife does not have authority over her own body
丈夫才有 请跟我来吧
"but yields it to her husband." Please come with me.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
你让我别无选择
You leave me no choice.
我们知道我们为什么来这里
We know why we came here.
这里是神的国度
This is god's nation.
耶和华给这个美丽的新国家赐予了他的恩典
The lord shed his grace on this beautiful new country.
这是我们的出埃及记
This was our exodus.
在这座丘陵上的城市
In this city on a hill,
我们将发展一个更纯粹的基督教
we will develop a purer form of christianity.
我们不是都同意
Hadn't we all agreed
抛开旧俗吗
to leave the old language behind?
我们不是都发誓要在这里做得更好吗
Hadn't we sworn to do things better over here?
新世界会把我们从旧世界的罪中解脱
The new world would free us from the sins of the old.
我们是人类的耀眼希望
We are the bright hope of humanity.
这里是应许之地
This is the promised land,
来到这里 我们就都成了神选之人
and by coming here, we have become his chosen people.
阿加莎
Agatha,
你能告诉大家你是怎么领受到召唤的吗
would you tell everyone how you received the calling?
我在家削土豆时
I was at home, peeling potatoes,
出现了巨大白光
when this huge white light appeared.
我看见白光中有个英俊的年轻男子
In that light, i saw a beautiful young man
有着白色翅膀
with white wings.
我问他是不是天使
I asked if he was an angel,
这个年轻男子点点头 露出了微笑
and the young man nodded and smiled.
阿里
Arie,
你能和我们分享一下你目睹的事吗
would you be so kind to share your story of witness with us?
我的差不多一样
For me, it was more or less the same thing,
但出现的不是男的
but it wasn't a man.
在我面前出现的是个美丽的年轻女子
It was a beautiful young woman who showed herself to me.
看见没 我们都是神选之人
You see? We are the chosen people.
显圣这种事并非在任何人身上
A visitation like that is not something that happens
都会发生 你必须争取它
to just anybody. You have to earn it.
安娜
Anna,
你能上前来吗
would you please come to the front?
你怎么说 安娜
What about you, Anna?
你领受到召唤了吗
Have you received the calling yet?
我还没受到这样的祝福
I have not been blessed in such a way.
在我们社区  每个成年人都领受到了召唤 而你却没有
In our community, everyone of age has received such a calling, you have not.
安娜 你做了什么让神如此愤怒
What did you do, Anna, to anger god this much?
我自己的妻子
My own wife,
没法受到神的青睐
who cannot find the lord's favor.
你让我感到耻辱
I am ashamed of you.
天父
Father,
我祈求我妻子对你和对我的爱会增加
I pray that my wife will grow in her love for you,and me.
愿她对我们的爱 注入所有真心
May she love us with all her heart,
所有灵魂 所有思想和所有努力
all her soul, all her mind, and all her might.
赐予我力量 引领她通向
Give me the strength to lead her to the salvation
你恩典下的救赎
provided by your grace.
以耶稣之名 阿门
In Jesus' name, amen.
亲爱的
我要死了
不会的 不会死
这很正常 你这岁数的姑娘都会出现这样的情况
为什么
你现在是女人了 乔安娜
你的身体已做好生孩子的准备
你必须洗洗你女儿
You must wash your daughter.
她不洁净了
She is unclean.
但他从不帮一点忙
But he never raises a finger to help out.
这是女人的命运
It's a woman's fate.
谁说的
Says who?
圣经
Says the Bible.
这不公平
It's not fair.
你父亲是一名教士
Your father's a man of the cloth.
他侍奉神 尘世的家务杂活都留给了他的妻子
He serves god and leaves earthly chores to his wife.
你想干嘛
What do you want?
让我们单独待会儿 我得和这姑娘谈谈
Leave us alone, i have to talk to the girl.
你母亲跟你说了成为女人意味着什么吗
Has your mother told you what it means to be a woman?
说了
Yes.
这血已渗入你的生活
And the blood has penetrated into your life
已驱走你的纯洁
and driven out the innocence.
不用多久 男人们就会开始发现你的魅力
It won't be long before men start to find you attractive.
女人 我知道你在偷听
Woman? I know you're listening.
从现在起 你要把乔安娜当女人来对待
From now on, you must treat Joanna like a woman.
从今天起 猪就由你来管了
As of today, you will do the hogs.
嘿
Hey.
你好 小姐
Hello, lady.
我看到了水泵
I saw the pump.
希望你能
I was hoping you'd be kind enough
让我解渴
to let me quench my thirst.
请允许我表达我最深切的感谢
Allow me to express my deepest thanks.
你们从哪来
Where are you men from?
说来话长
Oh, that's a long story.
以后有机会再说
Maybe some other time.
他怎么办
What about him?
你照顾好他吧
You take care of him.
我猜你是个基督徒
After all, you are a Christian, I assume?
该死的
God damn me.
去马那
Get the horse.
我父母会发现你们两个的
My parents would find you two.
然后把该死的马鞍拿下来
Then get the goddamn saddle.
快走
Go!
快走 离开这里 快
Go on, get out of here! Go on!
得把该死的子弹取出来
Damn bullet needs to get taken out.
然后我也需要照顾
And I need taking care of too.
我父亲会不高兴的
My father won't like that.
是啊…
Yeah...
你知道吗 别他妈告诉他
You know what? Don't fuckin' tell him.
要取了
Here it comes.
我想 是时候自我介绍了
I reckon, it's about time i introduced myself.
我叫塞缪尔
I'm Samuel.
很高兴认识你
It's nice to meet you...
乔安娜
Joanna.
谢谢
Thank you.
这姑娘长得真快
The girl is growing fast.
嗨 亲爱的
Hi, sweetie.
他在发烧
He's running a fever.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
因为据说测体温的最佳方式
'Cause they say the best way to take someone's temperature
是用嘴唇 是吧
is with the lips, huh?
你现在多大了 孩子
How old are you now, child?
十三
Thirteen.
一个完全成年的女人…
A full-grown woman has...
在生活中有着小女孩不能履行的职责
Has duties in life that a young girl can't fulfill.
是我们的主亲自给予的职责
Duties imposed by our lord himself.
请跟我来
Come with me, please.
你母亲总不承担
Your mother does not always assume responsibilities
她应当承担的职责
the way she should.
她不依从她的自然职责
She does not comply with her natural duties.
你明白我的意思吗
Do you understand what I mean?
神让你这么快成为女人 是有原因的
God has made you a woman so soon for a reason.
你或许觉得这是诅咒
You might believe it to be a curse,
但他做的一切都是有原因的
but he has a reason for everything.
你就如使徒保罗笔下所写的那样
You have, as the apostle Paul put it,
过了年岁
"passed the flower of your age."
这可不对
This is not right.
你看到血了
You have seen the blood.
她只是个孩子
She's just a child.
我无需回应你 我只回应神
I need not answer to you. Only to god.
不用了 谢谢 安娜
No, thank you, Anna.
我们的神另有安排
Our god has other plans.
不会有事的
It'll be all right.
双手拿好
Use both hands.
别让爆破吓到你
Don't let the blast scare you.
你现在是成年人了 乔安娜
You're a grown woman now, Joanna.
我能和你谈会儿吗
Could I talk to you for a moment?
我想道歉
I want to offer my apologies.
我不让你行使你的权利
I withheld from you that to which you have a right.
这是我的错
That was wrong of me.
我接受道歉
Apology accepted.
让我来弥补吧
Let me make it up to you.
太晚了
It's too late for that.
我看到了你看她的样子
I have seen how you look at her.
她是你的亲生女儿
She's your own daughter.
这是罪
It's a sin.
不一定
It does not have to be.
若有人以为自己待他的女儿
"If any man thinks that he is behaving himself unseemly
不合宜 女儿也过了年岁
"towards his virgin daughter, if she pass the flower of her age,
事又当行 他就可随意办理
"and if need so requires, let him do what he will,
不算有罪 叫二人成亲就是了
"he is not sinning, let them marry."
你这肮脏的猪
我要训教你
You shall be scolded.
好姑娘
Good girl.
你让人等得真够久的
That sure as hell took long enough.
你去哪
Where are you going?
我去拉屎
Gonna take a crap.
你要我把这个放哪
Where do you want me to put this?
我急需绳子
I need some rope and I need it fast.
能帮我弄到吗
Can you get that for me?
很好
Good.
我不得不那么做
I had to do that.
不然他会趁机杀了我
If I hadn't, he'd have killed me at some point.
他死总比我死好
Better him than me, I'd say.
我曾听过一个故事
I heard that story once,
有关于忍气吞声
the one about turning the other cheek and all that.
说那种话的人
The only person who'd say something like that
就是在掌控一切
is someone who's in control.
就是不希望你反抗他
Someone who doesn't want you to stand up to him.
我看见你母亲了
I've seen your mother.
她就是那种忍气吞声的人
She's the kind of person that turns the other cheek.
你和她一样吗
Are you like her?
你为什么让他这么做
Why do you let him do this?
我绝不会像你这样
I'll never be like you.
绝不会这么活下去
This is no way to live.
我宁愿死
I'd rather die first.
蛇对女人说
The serpent said to the woman,
你不一定死
"you surely will not die!
因为神知道 你吃的日子
"For god knows that in the day you eat from it,
眼睛就明亮了
"your eyes will be opened,
你便如神 能知道善恶
"and you will be like god, knowing good and evil."
于是女人见那棵树的果子好作食物
And when the woman saw that the tree was good for food,
也悦人的眼目
and was a delight to the eyes,
且是可喜爱的 能使人有智慧
and that the tree was desirable to make one wise,
就摘下果子来吃了
she took from its fruit and ate.
然后耶和华神对女人说
And then the lord god said to the woman,
我必多多加增你怀胎的苦楚
"i will greatly multiply your pain in childbirth.
你生产儿女必多受苦楚
"In pain you will bring forth children,
你必恋慕你丈夫
"yet your desire will be for your husband.
你丈夫必管辖你
"And he will rule over you."
这是亵渎
This is an abomination.
This is an abomination!
她难道不知道她的身体
Does she not know that her body is
是从神那受领的圣灵之殿吗
the temple of the holy spirit, which she received from god?
这是一种耻辱
This is a disgrace.
她会在地狱受到惩罚
She will be punished in hell.
她会被变成一棵荆棘树
She will be transformed into a thorny tree,
在折磨之林中 被鹰身女妖所惩罚
and in a tortured wood, she will be punished by harpies,
她们会用利爪挖凿她
who will dig their sharp talons into her,
直到她鲜血淋漓
until the blood comes flowing down!
主啊
Oh, lord.
原谅我吧
Forgive me.
你知道我试图让她
You know I have tried to keep her
坚守在通向悔改的狭窄之路上
on the narrow way to repentance.
但就如马太福音所言
But like the gospel of Matthew says,
宽广的路总是通向毁灭
"the way is broad that leads to destruction."
我劝说她
I spoke to her.
我责打她
I chastised her.
但无济于事
But to no avail.
我失败了
I failed.
好了 好了
There, there.
没事了
It's all right.
我到年龄了
I'm old enough.
我知道
I know.
神已经原谅了我
God has forgiven me.
我准备好了
I am ready.
谢谢你 主 谢谢你 全能的主
Thank you, lord. Thank you, almighty.
你看见并预见一切
You saw, and foresaw all.
你看见我妻子没做到你对她所期望的
You saw that my wife did not do what you expected of her.
她不爱你 也不爱我 而我女儿会爱的
That she did not love you, or me, as my daughter will.
罗得和他的女儿们结婚了 而她们是他的孩子
Lot lay with his daughters and they bore children unto him.
乔安娜和我要缔结婚姻关系
Joanna and I shall enter a state of matrimony
她会怀上我的孩子
and she shall bear my children.
我们会带给你喜乐与荣耀
We shall be joyous and honor you.
放开我
Let me go!
别害怕
Fear not.
不要
No!
这是神的旨意 我们是他的选中之人
It is the will of god. We are his chosen ones.
两个人以神之名许下誓言时
When two people make their vows in the name of the everlasting,
他们会宣称属于彼此 深深相爱
they pronounce their wish to belong to each other fully in love.
他们将一起探寻神想从他们生活中得到什么
Together they shall search for what god wants from their lives.
他们将一起履行他们的职责
Together they shall perform their duties
并照顾好他们的家庭
and care for their family.
我父亲是彻头彻尾的混蛋
My father was a real bastard.
他常拿雪茄烫我手臂 这该死的虐待狂
He used to put cigars out on my arm, the sadistic fuck.
他是个变态 就和你一样
And he was a pervert, just like you.
我在九岁时杀了他
I killed him when I was nine years old.
你是谁
Who are you?
你女儿很特别
You have a real special daughter.
她理应得到自由
She deserves to be free.
你觉得你能进来拿走属于我的东西吗
You think you can come in here and take that which belongs to me?
没错 你觉得呢
Yeah. What do you think?
神会从天而降来救你?
That god's gonna come down here and save you?
我就如神
I am as god.
他也如我
He is as I am.
我会爱你的
I will love you.
你要学会爱我
And you will learn to love me.
- 这是神的旨意  - 我要杀了你
- It is god's will.  - I will kill you.
这阻止不了我
That would not stop me.
你疯了
You're mad.
那个人是谁
Who was that man?
他给你灌输了愚蠢的想法
He put foolish thoughts in your mind.
他帮助了我 我爱他
He helped me. I love him.
不是 那不是爱
No, you do not.
那是淫欲
It is lust.
是爱
Yes.
我要打得你不再像你母亲那样
I will beat your mother out of you.
是时候了
The time has come.
我会温柔的
I will be gentle.
第四章
惩罚
他不会罢休的 对吗
He ain't never gonna stop, is he?
我不会有事的
I'll be fine.
我们到了吗
Are we there yet?
快回去睡觉
什么情况
What was that?
放手 放开我
No, let me go!
- 待在那  - 马修
- Stay there!  - Matthew!
珊慕 不管有什么事都别出来
Stay there, Sam. Whatever happens!
马修
Matthew!
妈妈
Mama!
马修
Matthew!
莉兹
Oh, Liz...
我一直希望这地方有朝一日会属于伊莱
I'd always hoped this place would be Eli's someday.
我意思是…
I mean...
他可以…
He could've...
怎么说呢
I don't know...
弄个伐木场什么的…
A sawmill or something...
你确定吗
Are you sure?
你以前开过枪吗
Have you ever fired one of those things before?
这是我的战斗
拿枪的应该是我
I should be the one holding the gun.
我要你留下陪珊慕
那么远开枪毫无用处
There's no use shooting from that distance.
这比你料想的更难
It's more difficult than you think,
尤其用这样的枪
especially with a gun like that.
在毕斯玛司时 我真的准备好原谅你了
I was truly prepared to forgive you, back in bismuth.
我爱你
I loved you.
你应该知道
You should have seen that.
可你却违抗我
You've turned against me,
就像你母亲那样
just like your mother.
但我再次被给予了另一个选择
But again, I have been provided with an alternative.
没错 乔安娜
That's right, Joanna.
你女儿会为你的所作所为受苦
Your daughter shall suffer for your actions.
我责打她时 我会让你看着
And I will make you watch as I chastise her.
之后 你会目睹我是如何让她变成女人的
And after that, you will witness how i make her a woman.
你觉得她在里面是安全的?
You believe she's safe in there?
我接近不了她?
That I cannot get to her?
你把她单独留下了 乔安娜
You left her alone, Joanna.
永远不要把你的心爱之人单独留下
Never leave your loved ones alone.
你现在应该懂了
You should know that by now.
我能对你做的最坏的事是什么呢 乔安娜
What is the worst thing i could do to you, Joanna?
幸好她睡着了
Lucky for her, she was asleep.
她什么都没看见
She did not see a thing.
怎么了
Huh, what...
要防备假先知
Beware of false prophets
他们到你们这里来 外面披着羊皮
who come to you in sheep's clothing...
里面却是残暴的狼
For inwardly, they are ravening wolves.
妈妈
Mama!
不 妈妈 妈妈
No, mama! Mama!
不
No!
妈妈
Mama!
我对你女儿会完全照做我对你所做的
I will do to your daughter exactly as I did to you.
我会尽量伤害你
I am going to hurt you as much as I can.
我就让门开着
I will leave the door open.
我给你带了这个过来
I brought you this.
你母亲跟你说了成为女人意味着什么吗
Has your mother told you what it means to be a woman?
许多人认为神不赞成暴力
Many people believe that god does not approve of violence.
他们就没读过他们的圣经
They have not read their Bible.
暴力洁净罪恶 净化心灵
"Violence cleanses evil. It purifies the heart."
你的心灵需要净化吗
Does your heart need purifying?
你有过不好的念头吗
Have you had bad thoughts?
或许和男人有关?
About men, perhaps?
你喜欢男人吗
Do you like men?
你出过血吗
Have you bled yet?
我是个注定要遭厄运的人 珊慕
I am a doomed man, Sam.
已无法被拯救
Beyond salvation.
我想做什么就做什么
I can do whatever I want.
小女孩仍有着纯洁的气息
Young girls still carry the scent of innocence.
年长的女人闻上去就不同
Older women smell different.
是时候了
The time has come.
人们觉得地狱难以忍受是因为那里的烈焰
People think it's the flames that make hell unbearable.
并不是这样
It's not.
而是因为没有爱
It is the absence of love.
嘿
Hey.
嗯哼
Mmm-hmm.
呀…
Well...
好久不见 莉兹
Long time no see, Liz.
那时我崩溃了
I was a broken man.
无法继续在那生活
Couldn't go on living there.
好在新来的传教士指引了我
Good thing the new preacher showed me
让我去别处试试
I had to go try somewhere else.
是他告诉我毕斯玛司在招副警长
He was the one, told me they was lookin' for deputies up in bismuth.
我在那开启了新的生活
I made myself up a new life there.
大约一年前 那里的警长遭到了枪击
About a year ago, the sheriff there got himself shot.
我被选任代替他的位置
And I was chosen to replace him.
我清理他的办公室时
And while I was cleaning out his office...
发现了这个
I found this.
[通缉令]
[2500美元赏金]
[犯谋杀罪 伊丽莎白·布兰迪 哑巴 没舌头]
你本该改名的 莉兹
You should've changed your name, Liz.
你觉得世界上叫
How many Elizabeth brundys
伊丽莎白·布兰迪的人有多少
you figure there are in this world?
而又有多少是没舌头的
And how many of 'em you figure don't got no tongue?
伊丽莎白·布兰迪
Elizabeth brundy,
你因谋杀你的前雇主兼弗兰克的地狱的业主
I hereby arrest you for the murder of frank blain,
弗兰克·布莱恩 而被捕了
your former employer and proprietor of frank's inferno.
你逃不出你过去的所作所为 莉兹
Your past done caught up with you, Liz.
时光荏苒 影像迷离
As life progresses, images blur.
独留回忆
All that remains are memories.
我清楚地记得她
I remember her well.
她是一名战士
She was a warrior.
始终掌控一切
Always in control.
我常会想她下沉时在想什么
I've often wondered what she was thinking about on her way down.
我会想她想到了我
I like to think she thought of me.
我会想她知道我长大后会变得坚强
I like to think she knew I would grow up to be strong.
我清楚地记得她
I remember her well.
至少我觉得是这样
At least I think I do.
我感觉她一直在我身边
It feels like she always stayed with me.
看守着我
Watching over me.
保护着我
Protecting me.
嘿 快来 放下那东西
Hey, come on. Put that down.
妈妈
Mama?
走吗
You coming?
译者｜微博@Emtee